Robert Loesch

https://www.linkedin.com/in/robertloesch/ https://googlecloudlab.github.io (608) 669-9900, rtloesch@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Cloud and hybrid technology thought leader and trusted customer advocate with 20+ years experience as a Technical Account Manager, Technical Sales Engineer, Architect, and Developer. Driving successful business outcomes and solving customer challenges through hands-on solutions building. Ability to communicate with developers and C-level executives alike. Public speaker and mentor with a passion for continued knowledge acquisition and growth. Master's degree in Management Information Systems and MBA degree. International work experience and fluency in English and German.

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Google Cloud - Technical Sales Manager, Enterprise Accounts

February 2020 - PRESENT

```
2023 Individual KPI: 20 Greenfield customers, Revenue (to-date): 87% of $4.5M, 4 New Logo Wins to-date

2022 Individual KPI: 8 customers (mix of Greenfield/Spenders), Bookings: 22% of $3M, Revenue: 99% of $2M, 2 New Logo Wins

2021 Individual KPI: 8 customers (mix of Greenfield/Spenders), Bookings: 73.5% of $2M, Revenue: 118.3% of $1.5M, 1 New Logo Win
```

- Established trusted advisor relationships and owned the technical relationship with Google Cloud customers. Responsibilities include the identification and qualification of business opportunities, managing product and solution briefings, proof-of-concept work, and the coordination to resolve technical blockers.
- Helped customers understand Google Cloud products and services and how to use them to solve their business problems.
- Recommended migration strategies, enterprise architectures, migration tools and cloud infrastructure required to successfully implement a complete solution using best practices on Google Cloud.
- Conducted certification study group office hours and mentored a group of Cloud Engineers at several customers for the Google Cloud Associate Cloud Engineer certification and certified 8 engineers at my customers.
- Led the efforts for planning and coordinating the Google presence at the THAT conference with approx. 1000 attendees. Worked with marketing on sponsorship of the event and presented at the conference.

IBM - Executive Architect

February 2005 - February 2020

 Developed and implemented enterprise-wide technology strategies by working closely with senior management at customers to understand the company's business goals and challenges, and then developed and implemented solutions that met those needs.

- Designed and implemented complex technical systems such as cloud migrations, data center consolidations, and new application development.
- Led a team of architects to provide an assessment of an insurance platform on IBM Cloud in terms of cost optimization, stability, performance, flexibility, and openness.
- Led a DevOps transformation initiative at a large Telco provider by establishing the architecture and roadmap, including the use of monitoring, tracing, and telemetry tools to establish visibility into platforms.
- Led the infrastructure work stream and guided the development team for the IBM Watson Natural Language Processing component integration with a Tax Workbench at a large professional services firm.
- IBM Global Business Services representative at a major cloud conference to advise clients and booth visitors on the Journey to Cloud and application modernization.
 Assisted with developing the storyline and demos for the event.
- Instructor and mentor for IBM internal Red Hat OpenShift training classes and assisted 26+ students to become Red Hat OpenShift certified.

DEGREES

MBA in General Business, University of Wisconsin - Madison, United States of America, 2003 Diplom Wirtschaftsinformatiker, (Masters in Management Information Systems), University of Erlangen-Nuernberg, Germany, 1998

RECENT EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATIONS

Northwestern/Kellogg Chief Digital Officer Program, December 2022 - present University of Wisconsin Data & Analytics Bootcamp, June 2022 - December 2022 Google Cloud L300 CE Proficiency Attestation, June 2022

Executive Presence & Storytelling for Customer Engineers, May 2022

Mastering Technical Sales, October 2020

Google Cloud Professional Certifications: Cloud Architect, Cloud Data Engineer, Cloud Security Engineer, Cloud Network Engineer, Cloud DevOps Engineer, Cloud Developer, Cloud Machine Learning Engineer, Cloud Database Engineer, Cloud Digital Leader, Associate Cloud Engineer, Workspace Administrator

Certified Kubernetes Administrator, March 2020

Red Hat Certified Specialist in OpenShift Administration, Red Hat Certified Specialist in OpenShift Application Development, Red Hat Certified Specialist in OpenShift Security, 2019-2020

PUBLIC SPEAKING

THAT Conference, July 2023: Introduction to Tensorflow

UW E-Business Consortium, November 2022: Data Engineering for Predictive Analytics

THAT Conference, July 2022: First Steps with Go workshop

Google Cloud Serverless Summit, November 2021: Serverless real-time data processing

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Cloud/Hybrid Platforms: Google Cloud, Red Hat Openshift, AWS, IBM Cloud

App Modernization: Microservices, Containerization, DevOps, SRE

Data & Analytics: Statistical Modeling, Jupyter Notebooks, Pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib, Beautiful

Soup, SQL, NoSQL, Postgres, MongoDB, Tableau, Hadoop, Machine Learning, D3, Plotly

Programming Languages: Go, Python, JavaScript, HTML, JSON